So let's get started with Webpack.
现在开始学习 webpack
We have Webpack CLI and Webpack installed as dependencies.
我们安装了 webpack CLI 和 webpack 作为依赖项
So they're showing up in our package.json file,
因此它们显示在 package.json 文件中
and we've got our basic app set up the way that we want.
我们按照自己想要的方式设置了基础应用
So let's start talking about some of the basics of Webpack.
现在来讨论一些 webpack 的基础知识
First off, Webpack one of
首先 webpack 特有的、其他构建工具没有的功能之一
build what's called a dependency tree for us.
就是为我们创建了一个叫做 "依赖关系树" 的东西
That dependency tree is going
依赖关系树从一个文件开始 随着 webpack 浏览过该文件
it's going to look for other dependencies that that file requires.
它会查找这一文件所需的其他依赖项
So let's say that this file is
假设这个文件就是
our JavaScript file and we are using a function that's coming from another file.
我们的 JavaScript 文件 并且其中使用了一个来自其他文件的函数
When Webpack sees that requirement for another file,
当 webpack 发现需要另外一个文件时
it's going to go to that required file,
它会跳转到那个需要的文件
and it's going to look through that.
浏览一遍
If it finds more dependencies in that file it will go to
如果在那个文件中找到更多依赖项 再跳转到
each one of the dependencies that's required to run that file.
运行该文件所必需的每一个依赖项
As it does that, it builds what we call a dependency tree,
以此类推 构建出了我们所说的 "依赖关系树"
a tree of all of the things that are required to run our app.
这个树上包括了运行应用所需的所有东西
That's one of the things that Webpack does that say,
这就是前面所说的 webpack 能做
Grunt and Gulp and Brunch don't,
而 Grunt 和 Gulp 以及 Brunch 不能做的事情之一
they just run rules.
后者仅仅是运行规则
But Webpack has knowledge of the entire structure of our application.
但是 webpack 知晓整个应用的结构
So in order to build any map like that Webpack is going to need a starting place.
要构建这样的一个 "地图" webpack 需要一个起始位置
So Webpack is going to have a starting place that we call entry,
因此 webpack 有个起始位置 叫做入口 (entry)
and that's the first core concept of Webpack is this entry point.
这就是 webpack 的第一个核心概念 入口点 (entry point)
Now, one of the cool things about Webpack4 which is
当前 webpack 的最新版本 webpack4
the newest version of Webpack is that it actually
有一项很酷的设定
creates a default setting for all of the required Webpack and things.
它为所有必需的 webpack 设置创建了默认值
So there is a default entry point that Webpack will set that just goes to
所以 webpack 也有一个默认的入口点 index.js
quite going to work for us because we already have expressed installed.
但这对我们不太适用 因为我们安装了 Express
So we're going to instead set up our own entry point.
所以要将默认设置替换成我们自己的入口点
To set up our own entry point or to set up any customized configs that are
要设置自定义的入口点或任何其他
outside of that default Webpack setting that they've created in Webpack4,
webpack4 创建的默认设置以外的自定义配置
we're going to use this file called Webpack config.js.
需要使用这个名为 webpack.config.js 的文件
Here, I have a repo that is an exact copy of the one that you can clone from GitHub,
这里是我从 GitHub 克隆的代码库副本
and in it we've got all the normal files and I have just added a
其中包含所有的常规文件 我刚才在
Webpack config.js file to the client folder.
client 文件夹中添加了 webpack.config.js 文件
With this file, we'll actually be able to override all those default values.
使用这个文件 我们实际上能够覆盖所有默认值
Before we get too far into that though,
在深入了解这些设置之前
the other core concepts that we're going to go over in
说一下本节课将要介绍的 webpack 其他核心概念
this lesson for Webpack are entry like we already mentioned,
就像前面提到过的入口 (entry)
the output, field loaders, plugins, and mode.
还有出口 (output)、加载器、插件和模式
So once we've gone through each one of those individually,
每掌握一个概念
we'll have a good picture of what Webpack is going to do for us.
我们都能更好地理解 webpack 的作用